<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<xliff version="1.0">
  <file original="global" source-language="en" datatype="plaintext">
    <body>

      <trans-unit id="1">
        <source>Family and Childhood</source>
        <target>家庭和童年</target>
      </trans-unit>

      <trans-unit id="1">
        <source>School and Religious Education</source>
        <target>學校和宗教教育</target>
      </trans-unit>

      <trans-unit id="1">
        <source>Palden Dorje's Illness</source>
        <target>生病</target>
      </trans-unit>

      <trans-unit id="1">
        <source>Palden Dorje Disappears</source>
        <target>失蹤</target>
      </trans-unit>

      <trans-unit id="1">
        <source>Meditation Begins</source>
        <target>禪修開始</target>
      </trans-unit>

      <trans-unit id="1">
        <source>Snakebite and Miracles</source>
        <target>被蛇咬和奇蹟</target>
      </trans-unit>

      <trans-unit id="1">
        <source>Wandering to Bara district</source>
        <target>到Bara區修行</target>
      </trans-unit>

      <trans-unit id="1">
        <source>Meditating in pit</source>
        <target>在地窖修行</target>
      </trans-unit>

      <trans-unit id="1">
        <source>Preaching in Halkhoriya jungle</source>
        <target>在Halkhoriya叢林宣講</target>
      </trans-unit>

      <trans-unit id="1">
        <source>Buddhist background</source>
        <target>佛教背景</target>
      </trans-unit>

      <trans-unit id="1">
        <source>Feats of inedia</source>
        <target>斷食</target>
      </trans-unit>

      <trans-unit id="1">
        <source>Reappearance in Ratanpur jungle</source>
        <target>重現Ratanpur叢林</target>
      </trans-unit>

      <trans-unit id="1">
        <source>New Appearance in 2009</source>
        <target>重現於二零零九年</target>
      </trans-unit>

      <trans-unit id="1">
        <source>Maha Sambodhi Dharma Sangha (earlier Palden Dorje, born Ram Bahadur Bomjan) was born on April 10, 1990 between 2:25am and 4am (information on date and time is still controversial and will be checked and clarified) in Ratanpur village, Bara district, Nepal.</source>
        <target>Maha Sambodhi Dharma Sangha (之前的法號為Palden Dorje, 俗名為Ram Bahadur Bomjan) 出生於四月十日, 西元一九九零年介於凌晨兩點二十五分和四點之間(日期與時間的資訊仍有爭議會再做確認) 位於尼泊爾Bara區, Ratanpur村. </target>
      </trans-unit>

      <trans-unit id="1">
        <source>Ram’s parents are farmers. His mother, Maya Devi was married at 12.  She had 5 sons and 4 daughters.  Ram was her third son.  When she was in her pregnancy, she found she was unable to eat meat without becoming ill.  The son, whom she named Ram, would not eat meat.  He would leave the house for long intervals from an early age.</source>
        <target>Ram的父母是農民, 他的母親, Maya Devi在12歲時結婚. 她有五個兒子和四個女兒. Ram是她的第三個兒子. 當她在懷有他時她發現她無法吃肉否則就會生病. 她的兒子, 取名為Ram, 則不肯吃肉. 他從很小的時候就會離開家裡很長一段時間.</target>
      </trans-unit>

      <trans-unit id="1">
        <source>Ram was always pleased to see a lama or a holy person and fastidiously imitated them.  He often seemed to be lost in thought and spoke little.  Whenever someone spoke to him, he would reply with a smile and would treat people of all ages equally.</source>
        <target>當Ram看到一位喇嘛或是僧人時總是很開心並且認真地模仿他們. 他時常有所思索的樣子或是很少說話. 當有人和他說話時他則會回以微笑並同等對待任何年紀的人.</target>
      </trans-unit>

      <trans-unit id="1">
        <source>According to his family and neighbors, Ram Bomjan often acted differently from his childhood friends, frequently observing other people in worship and praying himself. He has been described as being born with a peaceful nature, and would never get into a fight or kill an animal. Beginning at the age of five he only took leftovers for food, and went hungry if there was nothing.</source>
        <target>根據他的家人和鄰居, Ram Bomjan常和他孩童時期的朋友有不一樣的行為, 他時常觀察其他人朝拜或是自己也會祈禱. 他曾被形容為天生就俱有平和的心, 且從未和人起衝突或是殺害動物. 從五歲起他就只吃剩下的食物, 如果沒有了的話就餓着肚子.</target>
      </trans-unit>

      <trans-unit id="1">
        <source>He took his studies seriously and rarely played with other children, choosing instead to remain alone. He spent his time reading scriptures, meditating and worshipping the pipal tree which seemed to bring him joy. Seeing this behavior, Ram’s father sent him to study the scriptures of Lama Chhyoi with Samden Lama in their village.  After that Ram decided to embrace a religious life.</source>
        <target>他對待他的學習非常認真, 寧可選擇一個人且很少和其它的小孩玩在一起. 當他花時間在讀經文, 禪修和禮拜菩提樹時總是可以帶給他快樂. 他的父親看到這行為後就把他送去和Samden喇嘛學習Chhyoi喇嘛的經文. 在那之後Ram就決定要擁抱宗教的生活.</target>
      </trans-unit>

      <trans-unit id="1">
        <source>He was accepted into the monkhood by Som Bahadur Lama of Sudha, Ward 8 of Chitwan Village Development Committee.</source>
        <target>他跟隨位於Sudha的一位Som Bahadur喇嘛出家, 並監護於八位奇旺村發展委員會的會員. </target>
      </trans-unit>

      <trans-unit id="1">
        <source>Som Bahadur Lama said the following of his ward: “He was obedient. He never said ‘no’ to my word. He was friendly and sociable and he received education in that manner. He used to say frequently that his attention was much more drawn towards meditation than towards reading books.”</source>
        <target>Som Bahadur喇嘛說: "他總是很聽話. 對我的話他從不說不. 他很友善且容易相處, 在接受教導時也是如此. 他曾時常說相較於讀書他比較喜歡專注於禪修."</target>
      </trans-unit>

      <trans-unit id="1">
        <source>He was granted the initiation of</source>
        <target>他受了</target>
      </trans-unit>

      <trans-unit id="1">
        <source>Panchasheel</source>
        <target>五戒</target>
      </trans-unit>

      <trans-unit id="1">
        <source>Panchasheel is a Sanskrit word for a Buddhist initiation consisting of five vows, which are as follows:</source>
        <target>Panchasheel是佛教中接受五種戒律誓言的梵語, 為以下誓言</target>
      </trans-unit>

      <trans-unit id="1">
        <source>One must not kill animals (it is preferable to be vegetarian)</source>
        <target>不殺生（最好是素食）</target>
      </trans-unit>

      <trans-unit id="1">
        <source>One must not steal</source>
        <target>不偷盜</target>
      </trans-unit>

      <trans-unit id="1">
        <source>One must not lie</source>
        <target>不妄語</target>
      </trans-unit>

      <trans-unit id="1">
        <source>One must refrain from sexual misconduct</source>
        <target>不邪淫</target>
      </trans-unit>

      <trans-unit id="1">
        <source>One must not take intoxicating substances</source>
        <target>不飲酒或吸食毒品</target>
      </trans-unit>

      <trans-unit id="1">
        <source>Ram was initiated along with a group of nine other students. Ram refused to have his hair cut before the initiation, which was the common custom. It was after this initiation that Ram received the name,</source>
        <target>Ram和其他九位學生一起受戒皈依. Ram在還沒受戒皈依前拒絕剪掉頭髮這個習俗. 在受戒皈依儀式後Ram有了法號,</target>
      </trans-unit>

      <trans-unit id="1">
        <source>Palden Dorje</source>
        <target>Palden Dorje</target>
      </trans-unit>

      <trans-unit id="1">
        <source>It was the custom for the initiates to meditate for up to a month in a cave. Som Bahadur Lama was surprised at the ease with which Palden Dorje seemed to adapt to the situation requiring little sustenance. It was then that he realized that the boy had a natural talent for deep and prolonged meditation.</source>
        <target>依據習俗皈依的出家人需要在一個洞穴內禪修長達一個月, Som Bahadur喇嘛對於Palden Dorje似乎可以輕易地在沒有什麼食物的情況下維持禪修. 就在此時他了解到這個男孩天生就俱有可以進入深沈和長時間禪定的天賦. </target>
      </trans-unit>

      <trans-unit id="1">
        <source>After completing his Buddhist education for two years, all nine initiates went to Lumbini, the birthplace of Lord Buddha, for sightseeing. Palden Dorje seemed utterly taken by this place and it seemed to deepen his religious resolve. The other eight initiates returned but he refused to return. Instead, he went to Dehradun to further his religious education with the Gurus of Dehradun. Later he returned to Nepal to the beautiful lakeside city of Pokhara.</source>
        <target>在完成了兩年的佛法修習後, 所有九位學生都去佛陀的誕生地Lumbini去參觀. Palden Dorje似乎完全被這個地方攝受住且更加堅定了他宗教的決心. 其他八個學生都回去了但是他拒絕回去. 相反地他去和Dehradun的高僧們繼續學習. 之後他就回到尼泊爾美麗的波卡拉湖邊區.</target>
      </trans-unit>

      <trans-unit id="1">
        <source>Here it was that Palden Dorje became ill, and was unable to move his lower body.  Distressed, his teachers sent him home to recover.  During this time, Palden Dorje implored his family not to sacrifice any animals or take any alcohol otherwise further complications would arise.  He got better, but was still limping when he disappeared from his home the night of  May 16, 2005.</source>
        <target>就在此時Palden Dorje生病了且病到無法移動下半身. 難過之餘, 他的老師把他送回家修養. 在這段期間Palden Dorje請求他的家人不要殺害任何動物或是喝酒否則會產生更多的併發症. 他之後比較康復了, 但是在二零零五年五月十六日深夜離家時仍然行動不便.</target>
      </trans-unit>

      <trans-unit id="1">
        <source>When his mother became aware of the situation, she alerted the village, and everyone joined in the search for him.  A local boy claimed to have seen him while he was shaking a mango tree.  Palden Dorje had come up and picked up a mango, and stepped fully clothed into the river. “I thought you had disappeared,” – the boy remarked to Palden Dorje.</source>
        <target>當他的母親發現這情形時, 她通知了村民並且所有人都加入了協尋行列. 一個當地的男孩說當他正在搖一棵芒果樹時有看到他. Palden Dorje過來並撿起了一顆芒果然後就走入了河中. "我以為你不見了“ --這個小男孩向Palden Dorje這麼說.</target>
      </trans-unit>

      <trans-unit id="1">
        <source>“Have I?” – Palden Dorje  replied. – “You’d better go home, and be careful not to touch me.” The boy ran home to tell his story, but nobody believed him at first.  Palden Dorje’s relatives went to the ravine.  Palden Dorje smiled at them when they found him as was his habit.  They told him to come home.  “I’ll go home at four o’clock,” – Palden Dorje said.  His family decided it would be wise to keep an eye on him, and so some of his siblings stayed with him.</source>
        <target>“我有嗎？”-- Palden Dorje這麼回答. --"你最好趕快回家, 且小心不要碰到我.“ 這小男孩跑回家後並告訴其他人這件事, 但起初沒人相信. Palden Dorje的親戚去到了河邊. 當他們找到他時Palden Dorje就像往常一樣向他們微笑. 他們要他回家. "我會在四點回家“ -- Palden Dorje說. 他的親戚覺得還是要有人看著他, 所以他的一些親戚留下來陪他.</target>
      </trans-unit>

      <trans-unit id="1">
        <source>At four o’clock, he picked up a couple of mangoes and began to eat one.  He told his little brother to bring him water, rice, his lama robes, a rosary and a picture of Buddha.  His little brother obeyed.  Palden Dorje’s sister came to tell Palden Dorje to come home at once.  Seeing how emaciated he looked from his previous  illness, she cried and begged him to come home.  Palden Dorje told her to stop crying, and she went home.</source>
        <target>到了四點時他拿起了一個芒果並吃了起來. 他告訴他的弟弟幫他帶水, 米, 他的喇嘛袍, 念珠和一張佛陀的照片. 他的弟弟照做了. Palden Dorje的姐姐叫他回家. 看到他因之前的病如此憔悴她便哭著求他回家. Palden Dorje告訴她不要哭了, 她就回家去了.</target>
      </trans-unit>

      <trans-unit id="1">
        <source>Then Palden Dorje, sitting in a meditative posture seemed to go into a trance.  He began to ask himself questions and answer them out loud. The other villagers came and told Palden Dorje to stop being silly and come home.</source>
        <target>Palden Dorje以禪坐的姿勢坐著並好像進入發呆的狀態. 他開始問他自己問題並且大聲地回答出來. 其他的村民告訴他別發顛且趕快回家.</target>
      </trans-unit>

      <trans-unit id="1">
        <source>They feared he must be ill or crazy.  When Palden Dorje’s older brother touched him, Palden Dorje’s body became exceedingly hot and turned red. “Please leave me alone, or one of us may die,” – Palden Dorje said. – “If anyone disturbs me or my things at midnight, I will have to meditate for 20 years, but if all goes well, I will meditate for 6 years.”</source>
        <target>他們怕他已經生病或是發瘋了. 當Palden Dorje的哥哥碰他時, Palden Dorje的身體則變得非常熱且發紅. "請讓我獨處, 否則我們其中一人可能會死“ -- Palden Dorje說. "如果有人干擾我, 我則必須要禪修二十年, 否則如果一切順利, 我將會禪修六年." </target>
      </trans-unit>

      <trans-unit id="1">
        <source>Then Palden Dorje, followed by his brother, and at a distance by the villagers set out to find a good meditation  place in the forest. His parents insisted he take some food and water with him.  Finally, he reached his destination  at 11:00 AM on May 18, 2005. This was the day the villagers of Ratanpur celebrated</source>
        <target>Palden Dorje, 在哥哥以及村民在維持一定距離的跟隨下, 出發去森林找一個適合禪修的地方. 他的父母堅持要他帶一些水和食物. 最後, 他在二零零五年五月十八日早上十一點找到了目的地. 這天剛好是Ratanpur村民慶祝</target>
      </trans-unit>

      <trans-unit id="1">
        <source>http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Vesak</source>
        <target>http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Vesak</target>
      </trans-unit>

      <trans-unit id="1">
        <source>Buddha Jayanti (Vesak)</source>
        <target>佛誕的日子.</target>
      </trans-unit>

      <trans-unit id="1">
        <source>He settled himself under a pipal tree, having offered 10 kinds of fruit to the picture of Buddha.</source>
        <target>他在一棵菩提樹下安頓下來, 並且在佛陀的照片前供奉了十種水果.</target>
      </trans-unit>

      <trans-unit id="1">
        <source>About 30 villagers saw where Palden Dorje was meditating, and they left an offering of over a thousand rupees as was the custom at Buddha Jayanti.  On that night at 12:00,  some pranksters came to disturb Palden Dorje and steal the offering.  They quarreled over the money, and later accused each other in front of the villagers.  Having confessed, they asked Palden Dorje’s forgiveness.</source>
        <target>大約30個村民看到Palden Dorje在禪修, 在佛誕的習俗下他們留下了一千多盧比給他. 在當晚約十二點時一些人來打擾他並偷走了這些錢. 他們為了錢爭吵並在村民的面前指控對方. 後來他們認錯了並且請求Palden Dorje的原諒.</target>
      </trans-unit>

      <trans-unit id="1">
        <source>So Palden Dorje left the first meditation place and went north on the 24th of May, 2005.  At that time he gave six pipal leaves to his second elder brother telling him to keep them in oil.  He said that as long as his family kept the leaves, all would be well.  His relatives cried when he left.</source>
        <target>所以Palden Dorje離開了第一個禪修地並在二零零五年五月二十四日前往北方. 在此時他給他的二哥六片菩提樹葉並叫他要把它們放在油裡面保存. 他說只要他的家人保存好這些葉子, 一切都會沒事的. 他離開時他的親戚都難過地哭了.</target>
      </trans-unit>

      <trans-unit id="1">
        <source>Again the villagers were concerned about Palden Dorje’s whereabouts, and in the late afternoon, a cowherd had seen him in his new meditation site. The villagers sent some of his family to go and bring him home.  But Palden Dorje refused and  moved to another pipal tree in the east.</source>
        <target>再次地村民對Palden Dorje的下落感到憂心, 在某一個下午傍晚時, 一個牧牛人看到了他在新的禪修地. 村民叫他的一些親戚把他帶回家, 但是Palden Dorje拒絕了並且移到在東方的一顆菩提樹下.</target>
      </trans-unit>

      <trans-unit id="1">
        <source>Palden Dorje told his family that he must continue to meditate at all costs.  He drew a boundary around his meditation area, and the villagers and his relatives built a fence for him. More and more crowds gathered at the site, so Palden Dorje ordered that a hut be built and sealed with plastic on all sides wherein he remained for 15 days. After that Palden Dorje said, “I have received some energy so that I may now meditate under a tree outside”.</source>
        <target>Palden Dorje告訴他的家人無論如何他都一定要繼續禪修. 他在禪修地畫了一個範圍且村民和他的親戚幫他建立了柵欄. 越來越多的人群聚集了過來, 所以Palden Dorje要求建了一個小房舍並且把所有的外邊都用塑膠封起來, 他在裡面待了十五天. 在那之後Palden Dorje說“我已接受一些能量, 所以我可以在外面的樹下禪修了.</target>
      </trans-unit>

      <trans-unit id="1">
        <source>There was a terrible drought in the village. Palden Dorje told them to pray to a snake god and after 5 days, it started raining. In the 75th day of meditation, he opened the eyes and asked his elder brother to call him by the words: “Om Namó Gurú Búddha Gyáni”.</source>
        <target>當時村莊正有個可怕的旱災. Palden Dorje告訴他們向一個蛇神祈禱, 在五天之後, 天空開始下雨了. 在禪修第七十五天時他張開他的眼睛並要求他的哥哥叫他“Om Namó Gurú Búddha Gyáni”.</target>
      </trans-unit>

      <trans-unit id="1">
        <source>He returned to his meditation. Since that day he was addressed as</source>
        <target>他就繼續他的禪修了. 從那之後他就被稱為</target>
      </trans-unit>

      <trans-unit id="1">
        <source>“Om Namo Guru Buddha Gyani”</source>
        <target>“Om Namo Guru Buddha Gyani”</target>
      </trans-unit>

      <trans-unit id="1">
        <source>(Hail to the Master of the Wisdom of Buddha.)</source>
        <target>(向偉大俱足智慧的佛陀禮敬）</target>
      </trans-unit>

      <trans-unit id="1">
        <source>On August 18, 2005, Palden Dorje called together his friends who were lamas.  They asked him how it was that Palden Dorje was surviving without water. Palden Dorje replied that two snake gods protected him from either side.  That day Palden Dorje also changed his clothes and wore a white cloth called Ngag.</source>
        <target>在二零零五年八月十八日, Palden Dorje把他的一些喇嘛朋友叫了過來. 他們問他如何可以在沒有水的情況下生存下來. Palden Dorje告訴他們在他的兩旁有兩位蛇神在保護他. 那天Palden Dorje也換了衣服並穿上一件叫Ngag的白袍.</target>
      </trans-unit>

      <trans-unit id="1">
        <source>On November 6, 2005 snake bit Palden Dorje, and Palden Dorje’s body was poisoned. Palden Dorje sweated more than two liters while he continued to meditate, and thus he overcame the poison.  Palden Dorje’s followers believe that on that day he was enlightened, for the Bodhisattva has the ability to survive attached to a tree, soil and stone, to digest snake poison, to be unaffected by the wind and to understand the language of all creatures.</source>
        <target>在二零零五年十一月六月, 一條蛇咬了Palden Dorje讓他中了毒. 他在禪修過程中流了超過兩公升的汗, 也因此他克服了蛇毒. Palden Dorje的信徒相信在那天他悟道了, 因為菩薩有能力能在樹木, 土壤和石頭的環境下, 化解掉蛇毒, 不受風吹的影響並能了解所有生物的語言.</target>
      </trans-unit>

      <trans-unit id="1">
        <source>On November 8, 2005, Palden Dorje told the people that he did not have the energy of a Buddha, and he asked them not to publicize him as an incarnation of Buddha.</source>
        <target>在二零零五年十一月八日, Palden Dorje告訴人們他並沒有佛的能量且請不要把他說成佛的再來生. </target>
      </trans-unit>

      <trans-unit id="1">
        <source>On November 11, 2005 a bright light appeared shining from Palden Dorje’s head.  His followers cried with joy and became even more fervent.</source>
        <target>在二零零五年十一月十一日, 一條亮光從Palden Dorje的頭上散發出來. 他的追隨者喜悅地哭了並且追隨地更加地熱切.</target>
      </trans-unit>

      <trans-unit id="1">
        <source>“Leave me in peace, and there will soon be peace in the country,” – Palden Dorje said. However crowds ever increased and people chanted and set up a market place, according to Radio HBC 94 FM who visited the site on December 10, 2005. The crowds were kept at a distance of about 50 meters. All witnesses claimed that Palden Dorje neither ate, drank or left to relieve himself.  He just sat and meditated under the pipal tree. Baffled onlookers were ever increasing.</source>
        <target>“請讓我靜靜地獨處, 然後很快的這個國家就會有和平" - Palden Dorje說. 但根據HBC 94 FM電台在二零零五年十二月十日在當地的報導, 人群越集越多, 開始有人唱誦經咒並且在那裡設立了市集. 群眾被隔離在約五十公尺外. 所有的目擊者都說Palden Dorje沒有吃喝或是讓自己休息過. 他就這麼坐在菩提樹下禪修. 有越來越多疑惑的人們來看他.</target>
      </trans-unit>

      <trans-unit id="1">
        <source>There were stories of miracles: a</source>
        <target>還有一個神奇的故事：有一位</target>
      </trans-unit>

      <trans-unit id="1">
        <source>girl</source>
        <target>女孩</target>
      </trans-unit>

      <trans-unit id="1">
        <source>and a young man had gained the power of speech although they could not speak.</source>
        <target>和男孩因此從啞巴變成可以說話了.</target>
      </trans-unit>

      <trans-unit id="1">
        <source>After about ten months of meditation, Palden Dorje went missing on 11 March 2006. He gave no explanation, and some believed he had been abducted. His followers theorized that he went deeper into the woods to look for a quieter place to meditate.</source>
        <target>在約十個月的禪修後, Palden Dorje在二零零六年三月十一日突然失蹤了. 他並沒有給任何解釋, 一些人相信他被綁架了. 他的追隨者則認為他深入叢林去尋找更安靜的地方修行了. </target>
      </trans-unit>

      <trans-unit id="1">
        <source>Police abandoned a search for him after the possibility of foul play was eliminated. Suspecting money laundering, the authorities froze the bank account of the local committee managing the crowds, which had gathered more than Rs. 600,000 ($7950), but they found no evidence.</source>
        <target>警察在排除犯法的可能後就放棄搜尋了. 官方因懷疑當地的委員會有洗錢的可能所以凍結了他們的銀行戶頭, 此戶頭已經聚集了600,000 ($7950)盧比, 不過他們並未找到證據.</target>
      </trans-unit>

      <trans-unit id="1">
        <source>On 19 March, a group of Palden Dorje's followers met with him about 2 miles (3 kilometers) southwest of his meditation site. They say they spoke to him for thirty minutes, during which Palden Dorje said: "There is no peace here" and that he would return in six years, which would be in 2011 or 2012. He left a message for his parents telling them not to worry.</source>
        <target>在三月十九日, 一群Palden Dorje的跟隨者在他禪修地西南方約二英里(3公里)處發現他. 他們和他交談了約三十分鐘, 交談中他說"那裡沒有平靜"且他會在六年後回來, 也就是會在二零一一或二零一二年. 他要他們和他的父母說不用擔心.</target>
      </trans-unit>

      <trans-unit id="1">
        <source>On 25 December 2006, villagers in Bara district spotted Palden Dorje meditating. He was carrying a sword for protection in the jungle, reminding reporters that "Even Gautama Buddha had to protect himself," and claimed to have eaten nothing but herbs in the interim.</source>
        <target>在二零零六年十二月二十五日, Bara區的村民發現了Palden Dorje正在禪修. 他攜帶了一把刀為了在叢林內防身, 提醒村民說"即使是釋迦牟尼佛也需要保護他自己", 並且宣稱在此期間除了植物外什麼也沒吃.</target>
      </trans-unit>

      <trans-unit id="1">
        <source>He reiterated his six year commitment to Buddhist devotion, and said he would allow people to come and observe him, as long as they remained at some distance and didn't bother him. When a reporter pointed out that pilgrims to his meditation site would be making donations in his name, he asked for the donations to not be abused or used for commercial purposes. A new wave of visitors came to see him and pray at his new meditation spot. On 8 March 2007 he left Bara district to again find a quieter place to meditate.</source>
        <target>他重申了他的六年佛教修行並且允許人們在維持一定距離且不打擾他的情況下可以來看他. 當記者說許多來到他禪修地的信眾會以他的名義來接受捐獻, 他則要求不要濫用這些捐款且不要做為商業用途. 另一波人潮前來新的禪修地朝拜他. 在二零零七年三月八日他則離開了Bara區去尋找更安靜的禪修地了.</target>
      </trans-unit>

      <trans-unit id="1">
        <source>On 26 March 2007, Inspector Rameshwor Yadav of the Area Police Post Nijgadh, found Palden Dorje inside a bunker-like ditch seven feet square. A police team under Yadav's command had gone to the place after word had spread of Palden Dorje meditating underground. “His face was clean and hair was combed well,” – Yadav said.</source>
        <target>在二零零七年三月二十六日, Nijgadh警察Rameshwor Yadav, 發現Palden Dorje在一個七呎平方大溝狀的地窖內. 在有傳言Palden Dorje在地底下禪修的情況下Yadav命令一個警察小組前往察看. "他的臉很乾淨而且頭髮也梳地很好." - Yadav說.</target>
      </trans-unit>

      <trans-unit id="1">
        <source>According to him, the bunker had been cemented from all sides and fitted with a tiled roof. Indra Lama, a local deployed as Palden Dorje's caretaker since the beginning of his intensive meditation, said the bunker was prepared per Palden Dorje's request. “After granting audience a week ago, he expressed his desire to meditate inside the ground; so we built it,” – he said.</source>
        <target>根據他的說法, 這地窖的四周都被水泥封住且加了一個磚瓦的屋頂. Indra喇嘛, 是從Palden Dorje開始禪修就幫忙協助他的人, 說這是依據Palden Dorje的要求建立的. "在一個禮拜前允許群眾來看他之後, 他便表示他希望能夠在地底下禪修, 所以我們就幫忙建了它." - 他說.</target>
      </trans-unit>

      <trans-unit id="1">
        <source>On 2 August 2007, Palden Dorje</source>
        <target>在二零零七年八月二日, Palden Dorje</target>
      </trans-unit>

      <trans-unit id="1">
        <source>addressed a large crowd</source>
        <target>對群眾作了宣講</target>
      </trans-unit>

      <trans-unit id="1">
        <source>in Halkhoriya jungle in Bara district of southern Nepal. The Namo Buddha Tapoban Committee, which is devoted to looking after Palden Dorje, assembled the meeting.</source>
        <target>於尼泊爾南方Bara區的Halkhoriya叢林. 這次的集會是由自願負責照顧Palden Dorje的Namo Buddha Tapoban委員會所發起的.</target>
      </trans-unit>

      <trans-unit id="1">
        <source>A notice about the boy's first-ever preaching was broadcast by a local FM radio station, and the committee also invited people by telephone. Around three thousand people gathered to listen to Palden Dorje's address. A video was made of the event. According to Upendra Lamichhane, a blogger who wrote an article and took pictures of the meeting, Palden Dorje's message was, "The only way we can save this nation is through spirituality".</source>
        <target>這個男孩的第一次公開宣講被當地的FM廣播電台播放, 且委員會也透過電話邀請許多人前來. 大約有三千人前來聽Palden Dorje的演講. 這次的活動也有被錄影起來. 根據一個寫了文章和照了些相片的部落客Upendra Lamichhane, Palden Dorje的訊息是"只有透過心靈的修行才能拯救這個國家".</target>
      </trans-unit>

      <trans-unit id="1">
        <source>This was his speech:</source>
        <target>這是他的宣講內容</target>
      </trans-unit>

      <trans-unit id="1">
        <source>Palden Dorje is a member of the</source>
        <target>Palden Dorje是</target>
      </trans-unit>

      <trans-unit id="1">
        <source>Tamang</source>
        <target>Tamang</target>
      </trans-unit>

      <trans-unit id="1">
        <source>community, of which a majority practices</source>
        <target>族, 他們大多是信奉</target>
      </trans-unit>

      <trans-unit id="1">
        <source>Vajrayana Buddhism</source>
        <target>藏傳佛教.</target>
      </trans-unit>

      <trans-unit id="1">
        <source>Palden Dorje's story gained popularity because it resembled a legend from the Jataka Nidanakatha about</source>
        <target>Palden Dorje的故事吸引了很多人的注意因為它類似於本生因緣記關於</target>
      </trans-unit>

      <trans-unit id="1">
        <source>Gautama Buddha's</source>
        <target>釋迦牟尼佛</target>
      </trans-unit>

      <trans-unit id="1">
        <source>enlightenment, so much so that some devotees claimed Palden Dorje was the reincarnation of a Buddha.</source>
        <target>悟道的故事, 因此有些信徒宣稱他是佛陀的再來生.</target>
      </trans-unit>

      <trans-unit id="1">
        <source>However, on 8 November 2005 Dorje arose and said: “Tell the people not to call me a Buddha. I don't have the Buddha's energy. I am at the level of a rimpoche.” A rimpoche is a teacher, which indicates he believes he has achieved a significant amount. He said that he will need six more years of meditation before he may become a Buddha.</source>
        <target>但是, 在二零零五年十一月八日, Dorje起身並說了: "告訴人們不要叫我佛, 我還沒有佛的能量. 我目前還是在仁波切的階段" 仁波切是一個老師, 表示他已經有相當程度的修證了. 他說他修行六年之後有可能可以成佛.</target>
      </trans-unit>

      <trans-unit id="1">
        <source>According to his followers, Palden Dorje may have reached the stage of a</source>
        <target>根據他的信徒, Palden Dorje可能已經達到</target>
      </trans-unit>

      <trans-unit id="1">
        <source>Bodhisattva </source>
        <target>菩薩</target>
      </trans-unit>

      <trans-unit id="1">
        <source>a person on the path to attaining full enlightenment or buddhahood for the benefit of all sentient beings. According to the historical Buddha, Gautama Buddha, there were innumerable Buddhas before him and infinite Buddhas to come. Proponents also claim that Palden Dorje might also be</source>
        <target>的階段, 一個為了所有眾生的福祉而努力悟道成佛的聖者. 根據之前的佛陀, 釋迦牟尼, 曾說在他之前有無數的佛而在未來也有無數的佛會出現. 他的支持者也宣稱Palden Dorje可能是</target>
      </trans-unit>

      <trans-unit id="1">
        <source>Maitreya</source>
        <target>彌勒</target>
      </trans-unit>

      <trans-unit id="1">
        <source>Bodhisattva, the predicted successor to the historical Buddha.</source>
        <target>菩薩, 是預言中下一位出世的佛.</target>
      </trans-unit>

      <trans-unit id="1">
        <source>His mother's name is Maya Devi Tamang, the same first name as Buddha's mother. It is reported that his mother fainted when she found out that her son intended to meditate for an indefinite period.</source>
        <target>他的母親名叫Maya Devi Tamang, 和釋迦牟尼佛的母親有相同的名. 據說他母親聽到他要無限期地禪修時就昏倒了.</target>
      </trans-unit>

      <trans-unit id="1">
        <source>Those who have called him the "reincarnation of Buddha" have been criticised. Gautama Buddha taught that after</source>
        <target>那些稱他為佛的再來世的說法則被批評, 因為釋迦牟尼佛教導在</target>
      </trans-unit>

      <trans-unit id="1">
        <source>parinirvana</source>
        <target>涅盤</target>
      </trans-unit>

      <trans-unit id="1">
        <source>there is no more rebirth, therefore it is impossible to be a "reincarnation of Buddha", but it is possible to be another Buddha, another who has attained, or will attain, enlightenment.</source>
        <target>後就不會再落生死輪迴, 因此也不應該有佛的再來世, 但是是有可能會有另一尊佛出現, 一位將來會悟道成佛的人. </target>
      </trans-unit>

      <trans-unit id="1">
        <source>An average human being who stops drinking will die of dehydration in three to four days. According to the Guinness Book of Records the longest time a human has survived without water is 18 days. Palden Dorje, on the other hand, does not appear to break his meditation to eat or drink.</source>
        <target>一般人在三到四天沒有喝水的話就會因脫水而死. 根據金氏世界紀錄一個人最長可以不喝水而存活下來的時間是十八天. Palden Dorje則是在他的禪修期間都沒有吃喝.</target>
      </trans-unit>

      <trans-unit id="1">
        <source>Palden Dorje was observed not to leave the tree at least during the daytime, but nobody was allowed to approach him too closely. Between 5:00 p.m. and 5:00 a.m. nobody was allowed to see him, and a screen was erected for that purpose. Many people speculated that he ate and drank water during that time.</source>
        <target>Palden Dorje在白天時確實都可以在樹下被看到, 但是沒有人可以太接近他. 在下午五點後到早上五點之間則不允許有人可以看到他, 有個屏幕會擋住他. 許多人因此猜測他可能在那段時間有吃喝東西.</target>
      </trans-unit>

      <trans-unit id="1">
        <source>Some supporters believe that discussions of</source>
        <target>一些支持者認為有關</target>
      </trans-unit>

      <trans-unit id="1">
        <source>http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Inedia</source>
        <target>http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Inedia</target>
      </trans-unit>

      <trans-unit id="1">
        <source>inedia</source>
        <target>斷食</target>
      </trans-unit>

      <trans-unit id="1">
        <source>are irrelevant, and that the ability to sit nearly motionless in the same position day after day, with no regard for extremes of weather including a cold winter and a monsoon season, is notable. For example, American writer George Saunders visited Palden Dorje and observed him through a single night, and was impressed by Palden Dorje's perfectly still stature, even during an evening climate that seemed unbearably cold to the much better clothed journalist.</source>
        <target>的討論無關緊要, 而且可以在每天都如此坐著動也不動, 即使在酷寒的天氣或是雨季都保持如此就是相當不得了的事了. 例如, 有位美國作家George Saunders花一整晚的時間觀察Palden Dorje後, 他對Palden Dorje能夠這樣靜靜地坐著感到印象非常深刻, 即使是在對於多穿了許多衣服的作家都認為難以忍受的寒冷氣候下.</target>
      </trans-unit>

      <trans-unit id="1">
        <source>In December 2005, a nine-member government committee led by Gunjaman Lama watched Palden Dorje carefully for 48 hours and observed him not to take any food or water during that time. A video recording was also made of this test. However, they were unable to approach closer than 3 meters or take readings of his vital signs. The Nepalese government planned a more careful scientific study, but the plan was never carried out.</source>
        <target>在二零零五年十二月, 一個由Gunjaman喇嘛帶領的九個成員組成的政府委員會詳細地觀察了Palden Dorje四十八個小時確實發現他在那期間沒有吃喝任何東西. 同時也有錄影下來. 但是, 他們無法接近三公尺內去量測他的生命跡象. 尼泊爾政府計畫進行一個更詳盡的科學研究, 不過並沒有被實行.</target>
      </trans-unit>

      <trans-unit id="1">
        <source>In 2007, the Discovery Channel produced a documentary titled</source>
        <target>在二零零七年, 探索頻道製作了一個標題為</target>
      </trans-unit>

      <trans-unit id="1">
        <source>The Boy With Divine Powers</source>
        <target>靈修少年</target>
      </trans-unit>

      <trans-unit id="1">
        <source>On their first, four-day attempt, the film crew was required to stay outside a guarded barbed-wire fence, and their camera's infrared capabilities did not pick up evidence of a body at the base of the tree where Palden Dorje sat during their non-stop recording. On a second attempt a few weeks later, however, the film crew was able to film Palden Dorje continuously for 96 hours, day and night, during which time he did not drink any fluids or eat any food. According to scientists on the documentary, an average person would be expected to die from kidney failure after four days without drinking any fluids. The boy showed no signs of classical physical deterioration caused by dehydration. A close inspection by the film crew of the area around the tree where Palden Dorje was sitting revealed no hidden food supply or water pipes.</source>
        <target>的紀錄片. 他們第一次在隔著柵欄外嘗試要透過紅外線攝影連續地拍攝, 但是並沒有成功地錄到他的身體, 在幾個星期後的第二次嘗試, 則成功地不分晝夜連續拍攝了九十六個小時, 在那期間確實他並沒有吃喝任何東西. 根據紀錄片中的科學家, 一般人會因為四天沒有喝水而導致腎衰竭而死. 這男孩也沒有出現一般因缺水而產生的物理衰敗. 攝影團隊近距離觀察樹下也沒有發現藏有食物或是有水的管線.</target>
      </trans-unit>

      <trans-unit id="1">
        <source>On 10 November 2008, Palden Dorje</source>
        <target>在二零零八年十一月十日, Palden Dorje</target>
      </trans-unit>

      <trans-unit id="1">
        <source>reappeared and spoke</source>
        <target>對群眾宣講於</target>
      </trans-unit>

      <trans-unit id="1">
        <source>to a group of devotees in the remote jungle of Ratanpur, 150 km (95 miles) southeast of Kathmandu, near Nijgadh. His hair was shoulder-length and his body was wrapped in a white cloth.</source>
        <target>一個位於Ratanpur遠處的叢林, 加德滿都東南方一百五十公里（九十五英里）靠近Nijgadh的地方. 他的頭髮長即肩膀且身著白袍.</target>
      </trans-unit>

      <trans-unit id="1">
        <source>His devotees believe he attained enlightenment at Bodh Gaya in Bihar, which borders Nepal – the place where Siddartha Gautama attained enlightenment.</source>
        <target>他的信眾相信他在Bihar的Bodh Gaya, 尼泊爾的邊界處悟道了 - 這個地方是釋迦牟尼佛悟道成佛的地方.</target>
      </trans-unit>

      <trans-unit id="1">
        <source>biography_translated_by</source>
        <target>生平翻譯於</target>
      </trans-unit>
      
<!-- утф -->
    </body>
  </file>
</xliff>