<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<xliff version="1.0">
  <file original="global" source-language="en" datatype="plaintext">
    <body>

<!-- showSuccess -->
      <trans-unit id="1">
        <source>Family and Childhood</source>
        <target>סיפור חייו</target>
      </trans-unit>

      <trans-unit id="1">
        <source>School and Religious Education</source>
        <target>בית הספר ולימודי הדת</target>
      </trans-unit>

      <trans-unit id="1">
        <source>Palden Dorje's Illness</source>
        <target>מחלתו של פאלדן דורג'ה</target>
      </trans-unit>

      <trans-unit id="1">
        <source>Palden Dorje Disappears</source>
        <target>היעלמותו של פאלדן דורג'ה</target>
      </trans-unit>

      <trans-unit id="1">
        <source>Meditation Begins</source>
        <target>המדיטציה מתחילה</target>
      </trans-unit>

      <trans-unit id="1">
        <source>Snakebite and Miracles</source>
        <target>נשיכת נחש וניסים</target>
      </trans-unit>

      <trans-unit id="1">
        <source>Wandering to Bara district</source>
        <target>הנדידה למחוז בארה</target>
      </trans-unit>

      <trans-unit id="1">
        <source>Meditating in pit</source>
        <target>מדיטציה מתחת לאדמה</target>
      </trans-unit>

      <trans-unit id="1">
        <source>Preaching in Halkhoriya jungle</source>
        <target></target>
      </trans-unit>

      <trans-unit id="1">
        <source>Buddhist background</source>
        <target>הרקע הבודהיסטי</target>
      </trans-unit>

      <trans-unit id="1">
        <source>Feats of inedia</source>
        <target></target>
      </trans-unit>

      <trans-unit id="1">
        <source>Reappearance in Ratanpur jungle</source>
        <target>התגלות מחדש ביער ראטנאפור</target>
      </trans-unit>

      <trans-unit id="1">
        <source>New Appearance in 2009</source>
        <target></target>
      </trans-unit>

      <trans-unit id="1">
        <source>Maha Sambodhi Dharma Sangha (earlier Palden Dorje, born Ram Bahadur Bomjan) was born on April 9, 1990 between 2:25am and 4am in Ratanpur village, Bara district, Nepal.</source>
        <target>סמבודהי דהארמה סנגהא (לפנים פאלדן דורג'ה, אשר נולד רם בהדור בומג'אן) נולד ב 9 באפריל 1990 בין 2:25 ל 4:00 לפנות בוקר, בכפר ושמו רטאנפור מחוז בארה נפאל.</target>
      </trans-unit>

      <trans-unit id="1">
        <source>Ram’s parents are farmers. His mother, Maya Devi was married at 12.  She had 5 sons and 4 daughters.  Ram was her third son.  When she was in her pregnancy, she found she was unable to eat meat without becoming ill.  The son, whom she named Ram, would not eat meat.  He would leave the house for long intervals from an early age.</source>
        <target>הוריו של רם חקלאים, אימו מאיה דווי נישאה בגיל 12 וילדה 5 בנים ו 4 בנות, רם היה בנה השלישי. כשהיתה בהריון לא יכלה אימו של רם לאכול בשר מבלי להרגיש חולה וגם בנה הצעיר שנקרא רם סרב לאכול בשר, הוא היה עוזב את הבית לפרקי זמן ארוכים. </target>
      </trans-unit>

      <trans-unit id="1">
        <source>Ram was always pleased to see a lama or a holy person and fastidiously imitated them.  He often seemed to be lost in thought and spoke little.  Whenever someone spoke to him, he would reply with a smile and would treat people of all ages equally.</source>
        <target>רם תמיד שמח לפגוש לאמה (נזיר) או איש קדוש ומיד החל להתנהג כמוהם, רם לא הרבה לדבר ותמיד היה שקוע במחשבות, כשדיברו אליו הוא תמיד ענה בחיוך והתייחס לכל האנשים באופן שווה.</target>
      </trans-unit>

      <trans-unit id="1">
        <source>According to his family and neighbors, Ram Bomjan often acted differently from his childhood friends, frequently observing other people in worship and praying himself. He has been described as being born with a peaceful nature, and would never get into a fight or kill an animal. Beginning at the age of five he only took leftovers for food, and went hungry if there was nothing.</source>
        <target>לפי סיפורי המשפחה רם תמיד התנהג בצורה שונה מרוב חבריו, לעיתים קרובות מסתכל ולומד מאנשים בטקסים דתיים ומתפלל בעצמו, הוא נודע באופיו השליו והנוח ולעולם לא השתתף בקטטה או הרג חיה ןמגיל חמש הוא אכל רק מזון שנשאר ולעיתים אף נמנע מאכילה.</target>
      </trans-unit>

      <trans-unit id="1">
        <source>He took his studies seriously and rarely played with other children, choosing instead to remain alone. He spent his time reading scriptures, meditating and worshipping the pipal tree which seemed to bring him joy. Seeing this behavior, Ram’s father sent him to study the scriptures of Lama Chhyoi with Samden Lama in their village.  After that Ram decided to embrace a religious life.</source>
        <target>רם למד בשקדנות וברצינות ורק לעיתים רחוקות שיחק עם חבריו, בוחר להיות לבד ולהעביר את זמנו בקריאת ספרים, כתבים, תירגול מדיטציה וסגידה לעץ הפיפל(עץ פלפל ארוך) שנראה כי הוא מוצא בו אושר רב. בראותו את התנהגותו שלח אותו אביו ללמוד את תורתו של הלאמה צ'ייוי ולאמה סאמדן בכפרם, אחרי זה החליט רם לקבל עליו את אורח החיים הדתי.</target>
      </trans-unit>

      <trans-unit id="1">
        <source>He was accepted into the monkhood by Som Bahadur Lama of Sudha, Ward 8 of Chitwan Village Development Committee.</source>
        <target>הוא התקבל למסדר הנזירות של סום בהדור לאמה מ סודהה השומר השמיני של המועצה לפיתוח הכפר צ'יטואן.</target>
      </trans-unit>

      <trans-unit id="1">
        <source>Som Bahadur Lama said the following of his ward: “He was obedient. He never said ‘no’ to my word. He was friendly and sociable and he received education in that manner. He used to say frequently that his attention was much more drawn towards meditation than towards reading books.”</source>
        <target>סום בהדור לאמה מספר על רם שהיה ילד צייתן שאף פעם לא סרב להוראות, היה חברותי וכך הוא גם למד, רם תמיד אמר שהוא מעונין יותר בלימודי המדיטציה מאשר בקריאת ספרים.</target>
      </trans-unit>

      <trans-unit id="1">
        <source>He was granted the initiation of</source>
        <target>ואז הוא קיבל חניכה של</target>
      </trans-unit>

      <trans-unit id="1">
        <source>Panchasheel</source>
        <target>פאנצ'הסיל</target>
      </trans-unit>

      <trans-unit id="1">
        <source>Panchasheel is a Sanskrit word for a Buddhist initiation consisting of five vows, which are as follows:</source>
        <target>שהיא שיטת חניכה בודהיסטית המורכבת מחמישה נדרים:</target>
      </trans-unit>

      <trans-unit id="1">
        <source>One must not kill animals (it is preferable to be vegetarian)</source>
        <target>1. להימנע מהרג (עדיף לאכול מזון צמחוני)</target>
      </trans-unit>

      <trans-unit id="1">
        <source>One must not steal</source>
        <target>2. להימנע מגניבה</target>
      </trans-unit>

      <trans-unit id="1">
        <source>One must not lie</source>
        <target>3. להימנע מלשקר</target>
      </trans-unit>

      <trans-unit id="1">
        <source>One must refrain from sexual misconduct</source>
        <target>4. להימנע מקיום יחסי מין</target>
      </trans-unit>

      <trans-unit id="1">
        <source>One must not take intoxicating substances</source>
        <target>5. לא להשתמש בחומרים משכרים</target>
      </trans-unit>

      <trans-unit id="1">
        <source>Ram was initiated along with a group of nine other students. Ram refused to have his hair cut before the initiation, which was the common custom. It was after this initiation that Ram received the name,</source>
        <target>עוד 9 תלמידים קיבלו עליהם את החניכה. רם סרב לגזור את שיערו לפני טקס החניכה כמנהג המקומי ואחרי טקס החניכה הוא קיבל את השם</target>
      </trans-unit>

      <trans-unit id="1">
        <source>Palden Dorje</source>
        <target>פאלדן דורג'ה</target>
      </trans-unit>

      <trans-unit id="1">
        <source>It was the custom for the initiates to meditate for up to a month in a cave. Som Bahadur Lama was surprised at the ease with which Palden Dorje seemed to adapt to the situation requiring little sustenance. It was then that he realized that the boy had a natural talent for deep and prolonged meditation.</source>
        <target>מנהג מקובל היה לחניכים למדוט כחודש ימים במערה והקלות שבה פאלדן דורג'ה קיבל עליו צו זה הפתיעה את הלאמה סום בהדור ואז הוא הבין שתלמידו הוא מיוחד ויש לו באופן טיבעי את הנטיה למדיטציה עמוקה.</target>
	  </trans-unit>

      <trans-unit id="1">
        <source>After completing his education for two years, all nine initiates went to Lumbini, the birthplace of Lord Buddha, for sightseeing. Palden Dorje seemed utterly taken by this place and it seemed to deepen his religious resolve. The other eight initiates returned but he refused to return. Instead, he went to Dehradun to further his religious education with the Gurus of Dehradun. Later he returned to Nepal to the beautiful lakeside city of Pokhara.</source>
        <target>לאחר שהשלים את השכלתו הבודהיסטית במשך שנתיים תשעת התלמידים הלכו ל"לומביני" מקום הולדתו של לורד בודהא, פאלדן דורג'ה התרשם עמוקות ונראה היה שהביקור רק העמיק את החלטתו להמשיך בדרכו הדתית, בעוד חבריו נערכים למסעם חזרה פאלדן דןרג'ה סרב לחזור הביתה ובמקום זה הוא המשיך במסעו לדהרדון להמשיך את לימודיו עם החכמים של דהרדון, בשלב יותר מאוחר הוא חזר לנפאל לעיר היושבת על האגם הידועה בשם פוקרה.</target>
	  </trans-unit>

      <trans-unit id="1">
        <source>Here it was that Palden Dorje became ill, and was unable to move his lower body.  Distressed, his teachers sent him home to recover.  During this time, Palden Dorje implored his family not to sacrifice any animals or take any alcohol otherwise further complications would arise.  He got better, but was still limping when he disappeared from his home the night of  May 16, 2005.</source>
        <target>בדהרדון פאלדן נפל למשכב ולא יכל להניע את פלג גופו התחתון, מוריו שלחו אותו חזרה הביתה כדי שיוכל להחלים, בזמן שהותו בבית המשפחה פאלדן דורג'ה היפציר במשפחתו לא לאכול בשר או לצרוך אלכוהול אחרת יגרמו סיבוכים, מצבו השתפר אך עדיין צלע כאשר נעלם מבית משפחתו ב 16 למאי 2005.</target>
      </trans-unit>

      <trans-unit id="1">
        <source>When his mother became aware of the situation, she alerted the village, and everyone joined in the search for him.  A local boy claimed to have seen him while he was shaking a mango tree.  Palden Dorje had come up and picked up a mango, and stepped fully clothed into the river. “I thought you had disappeared,” – the boy remarked to Palden Dorje.</source>
        <target>כשאימו של פאלדן דורג'ה שמה לב למצבו היא הזעיקה את כל הכפר וכולם הצטרפו לחיפוש אחריו, נער מקומי טען שראה אותו מנער עץ מנגו "חשבתי שנעלמת " אמר הנער.</target>
      </trans-unit>

      <trans-unit id="1">
        <source>“Have I?” – Palden Dorje  replied. – “You’d better go home, and be careful not to touch me.” The boy ran home to tell his story, but nobody believed him at first.  Palden Dorje’s relatives went to the ravine.  Palden Dorje smiled at them when they found him as was his habit.  They told him to come home.  “I’ll go home at four o’clock,” – Palden Dorje said.  His family decided it would be wise to keep an eye on him, and so some of his siblings stayed with him.</source>
        <target>"באמת?" ענה פאלדן דורג'ה"עדיף שתלך הביתה והיזהר לא לגעת בי", הנער רץ לכפר וסיפר את הסיפור אך אף אחד לא האמין לו בתחילה, קרוביו של פאלדן דורג'ה הלכו לעמק, הוא חייך אליהם ואמר"אני אבוא הביתה בשעה 4:00", משפחתו החליטה להישאר בקשר עין איתו וכמה מאחיו נישארו במקום.</target>
      </trans-unit>

      <trans-unit id="1">
        <source>At four o’clock, he picked up a couple of mangoes and began to eat one.  He told his little brother to bring him water, rice, his lama robes, a rosary and a picture of Buddha.  His little brother obeyed.  Palden Dorje’s sister came to tell Palden Dorje to come home at once.  Seeing how emaciated he looked from his previous  illness, she cried and begged him to come home.  Palden Dorje told her to stop crying, and she went home.</source>
        <target>בשעה ארבע קטף פאלדן דורג'ה מנגו והחל לאכול, הוא אמר לאחיו הקטן להביא לו מים, אורז, את בגדי הלאמה שלו, מחרוזת תפילה ותמונה של בודהא, אחיו עשה כמתבקש ממנו, אחותו באה וציותה עליו לחזור הביתה מייד, לאור מצבו בעקבות המחלה אחותו התחילה לבכות והתחננה בפניו שיבוא הביתה עימה, פאלדן דורג'ה אמר לה להפסיק לבכות והיא הלכה הביתה.</target>
      </trans-unit>

      <trans-unit id="1">
        <source>Then Palden Dorje, sitting in a meditative posture seemed to go into a trance.  He began to ask himself questions and answer them out loud. The other villagers came and told Palden Dorje to stop being silly and come home.</source>
        <target>הוא ישב במדיטציה עמוקה והחל לשאול את עצמו שאלות בקול, תושבי הכפר שבאו לראות מה קורה ניסו לשדלו להפסיק וחשבו שהוא או חולה או יצא מדעתו.</target>
      </trans-unit>

      <trans-unit id="1">
        <source>They feared he must be ill or crazy.  When Palden Dorje’s older brother touched him, Palden Dorje’s body became exceedingly hot and turned red. “Please leave me alone, or one of us may die,” – Palden Dorje said. – “If anyone disturbs me or my things at midnight, I will have to meditate for 20 years, but if all goes well, I will meditate for 6 years.”</source>
        <target>כשאחיו נגע בו גופו הפך להיות חם למגע ואדום " אנא עזוב אותי לנפשי, או שאחד מאיתנו ימות" אמר לאחיו, אם מישהו יפריע לי או יגע בחפצי אצטרך למדוט למשך20 שנה, אבל אם לא יפריעו לי אז אוכל למדוט רק למשך 6 שנים.</target>
      </trans-unit>

      <trans-unit id="1">
        <source>Then Palden Dorje, followed by his brother, and at a distance by the villagers set out to find a good meditation  place in the forest. His parents insisted he take some food and water with him.  Finally, he reached his destination  at 11:00 AM on May 18, 2005. This was the day the villagers of Ratanpur celebrated</source>
        <target>ואז פאלדן דורג'ה ואחיו  הלכו לחפש מקום טוב למדיטציה ביער כשאנשי הכפר במרחק מה מהם, הוריו התעקשו שהוא יקח מזון ומים איתו, לבסוף הוא הגיע למקום ב 18 למאי 2005 ב 11:00 בבוקר, זה היה היום שתושבי ראטנפור חוגגים את </target>
      </trans-unit>

      <trans-unit id="1">
        <source>http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Vesak</source>
        <target></target>
      </trans-unit>

      <trans-unit id="1">
        <source>Buddha Jayanti (Vesak)</source>
        <target>בודהא ג'יאנטי ווסאק</target>
      </trans-unit>

      <trans-unit id="1">
        <source>He settled himself under a pipal tree, having offered 10 kinds of fruit to the picture of Buddha.</source>
        <target>הוא התיישב תחת עץ פיפל, והעלה פולחן 10 סוגי פירות שונים לתמונתו של בודהא.</target>
      </trans-unit>

      <trans-unit id="1">
        <source>About 30 villagers saw where Palden Dorje was meditating, and they left an offering of over a thousand rupees as was the custom at Buddha Jayanti.  On that night at 12:00,  some pranksters came to disturb Palden Dorje and steal the offering.  They quarreled over the money, and later accused each other in front of the villagers.  Having confessed, they asked Palden Dorje’s forgiveness.</source>
        <target>כשלושים כפריים ראו את מיקומו של פאלדן דורג'ה והם השאירו תרומה של כ 1000 רופי כמנהג המקומיים  בחגיגת הולדתו של בודהא.בסביבות 12:00 בלילה הגיעו כמה צעירים להפריע לפאלדן דורג'ה ולגנוב את הכסף, הם רבו על הכסף ואפילו לפני  תושבי הכפר הם התוודו על מעשיהם ולאחר מכן התנצלו בפני פאלדן דורג'ה.</target>
      </trans-unit>

      <trans-unit id="1">
        <source>So Palden Dorje left the first meditation place and went north on the 24th of May, 2005.  At that time he gave six pipal leaves to his second elder brother telling him to keep them in oil.  He said that as long as his family kept the leaves, all would be well.  His relatives cried when he left.</source>
        <target>פאלדן דןרג'ה עזב את מקום המדיטציה הראשון ויצא צפונה ב 24 למאי 2005, הוא נתן לאחיו 6 עלים של עץ הפיפל בתוך שמן ואמר לו שכל זמן שהמשפחה תשמור על עלים אלו לא יאונה כל רע למשפחה, מקורביו בכו כשהוא עזב.</target>
      </trans-unit>

      <trans-unit id="1">
        <source>Again the villagers were concerned about Palden Dorje’s whereabouts, and in the late afternoon, a cowherd had seen him in his new meditation site. The villagers sent some of his family to go and bring him home.  But Palden Dorje refused and  moved to another pipal tree in the east.</source>
        <target></target>
      </trans-unit>

      <trans-unit id="1">
        <source>Palden Dorje told his family that he must continue to meditate at all costs.  He drew a boundary around his meditation area, and the villagers and his relatives built a fence for him. More and more crowds gathered at the site, so Palden Dorje ordered that a hut be built and sealed with plastic on all sides wherein he remained for 15 days. After that Palden Dorje said, “I have received some energy so that I may now meditate under a tree outside”.</source>
        <target>פאלדן דורג'ה אמר למשפחתו שהוא חייב להמשיך למדוט בכל מחיר, הוא תחם את אזור המדיטציה בחבל וקרוביו ואנשי הכפר עזרו והקימו גדר, יותר ויותר אנשים הגיעו לאזור, פאלדן הורה להם להקים סככה עם כיסוי אטוום מפלסטיק  והוא ישב שם למשך 15 יום שבסיומם הוא יצא ואמר "קיבלתי אנרגיה כדי שאוכל לשבת למדוט בחוץ מתחת לעץ".</target>
      </trans-unit>

      <trans-unit id="1">
        <source>There was a terrible drought in the village. Palden Dorje told them to pray to a snake god and after 5 days, it started raining. In the 75th day of meditation, he opened the eyes and asked his elder brother to call him by the words: “Om Namó Gurú Búddha Gyáni”.</source>
        <target>בצורת קשה תקפה את אזור כפרו והוא אמר להם להתפלל לאלוהי הנחש ו 5 ימים לאחר מכן התחיל לרדת גשם. ביום ה75 של המדיטציה פתח פאלדן דורג'ה את עיניו ואמר לאחיו לפנות אליו בשם:" אום נאמו גורו    בודהא גיאני" וחזר למדוט, מאותו היום הוא נקרא בשם זה שמשמעותו: "יחי המורה של חוכמת הבודהא".</target>
      </trans-unit>

      <trans-unit id="1">
        <source>He returned to his meditation. Since that day he was addressed as</source>
        <target>וחזר למדוט, מאותו היום הוא נקרא בשם זה שמשמעותו:</target>
      </trans-unit>

      <trans-unit id="1">
        <source>“Om Namo Guru Buddha Gyani”</source>
        <target>"אום נאמו גורו בודהא גיאני"</target>
      </trans-unit>

      <trans-unit id="1">
        <source>(Hail to the Master of the Wisdom of Buddha.)</source>
        <target>שמשמעותו: יחי המורה של חוכמת הבודהא.</target>
      </trans-unit>

      <trans-unit id="1">
        <source>On August 18, 2005, Palden Dorje called together his friends who were lamas.  They asked him how it was that Palden Dorje was surviving without water. Palden Dorje replied that two snake gods protected him from either side.  That day Palden Dorje also changed his clothes and wore a white cloth called Ngag.</source>
        <target>ב 18 באוגוסט 2005 פאלדן דורג'ה קרא לכל חבריו הלאמה, הם שאלו אותו איך זה שהוא שרד ללא מזון ומים, הוא ענה ששני נחשים אלוהיים הגנו עליו משני צדדיו, באותו היום פאלדן גם החליף את בגדיו ועטה על עצמו גלימה לבנה הנקראת נגאג.</target>
      </trans-unit>

      <trans-unit id="1">
        <source>On November 6, 2005 snake bit Palden Dorje, and Palden Dorje’s body was poisoned. Palden Dorje sweated more than two liters while he continued to meditate, and thus he overcame the poison.  Palden Dorje’s followers believe that on that day he was enlightened, for the Bodhisattva has the ability to survive attached to a tree, soil and stone, to digest snake poison, to be unaffected by the wind and to understand the language of all creatures.</source>
        <target>ב 6 לנובמבר 2005 נחש הכיש את פאלדן דורג'ה וגופו הורעל, הוא המשיך למדוט בעודו מאבד יותר מ2 ליטרים של זיעה, וכך הוא ניטרל את הרעל, אנשיו מאמינים שבאותו היום פאלדן דורג'ה הפך להיות מואר שכן לפי האמונה אדם ב"דרך הבודהא" ביכולתו לשרוד כשהוא מחובר לעץ, אדמה,ואבן, רעל נחשים, פגעי מזג אויר ולהבין את שפת כל החיות.</target>
      </trans-unit>

      <trans-unit id="1">
        <source>On November 8, 2005, Palden Dorje told the people that he did not have the energy of a Buddha, and he asked them not to publicize him as an incarnation of Buddha.</source>
        <target>ב 8 לנובמבר 2005פאלדן דורג'ה אמר לאנשים שאין לו את הכוחות של ה אותו כגלגול חיים של הבודהא.</target>
      </trans-unit>

      <trans-unit id="1">
        <source>On November 11, 2005 a bright light appeared shining from Palden Dorje’s head.  His followers cried with joy and became even more fervent.</source>
        <target>ב 11 לנובמבר 2005 אור בוהק הופיע מעל לראשו של פאלדן דורג'ה, תלמידיו בכו מאושר והפכו מאמינים אפילו יותר.</target>
      </trans-unit>

      <trans-unit id="1">
        <source>“Leave me in peace, and there will soon be peace in the country,” – Palden Dorje said. However crowds ever increased and people chanted and set up a market place, according to Radio HBC 94 FM who visited the site on December 10, 2005. The crowds were kept at a distance of about 50 meters. All witnesses claimed that Palden Dorje neither ate, drank or left to relieve himself.  He just sat and meditated under the pipal tree. Baffled onlookers were ever increasing.</source>
        <target>"עיזבו אותי בשלווה ובקרוב תהיה גם שלוה במדינה" הוא אמר, אך למרות זאת יותר אנשים באו והתפתח באזור מעין יריד לפי הדיווחים של תחנת רדיו שביקרה את האזור ב 10 בנובמבר 2005. הקהל נשמר במרחק של 50 מטרים בערך, כל הנוכחים העידו שפאלדן דורג'ה אכל שתה או קם להתפנות,הוא פשוט ישב ומדט מתחת לעץ הפיפל.</target>
      </trans-unit>

      <trans-unit id="1">
        <source>There were stories of miracles: a</source>
        <target>היו גם סיפורים על ניסים: </target>
      </trans-unit>

      <trans-unit id="1">
        <source>girl</source>
        <target>נערה </target>
      </trans-unit>

      <trans-unit id="1">
        <source>and a young man had gained the power of speech although they could not speak.</source>
        <target>ובחור צעיר התחילו לדבר אפילו ולא יכלו קודם לדבר</target>
      </trans-unit>

      <trans-unit id="1">
        <source>After about ten months of meditation, Palden Dorje went missing on 11 March 2006. He gave no explanation, and some believed he had been abducted. His followers theorized that he went deeper into the woods to look for a quieter place to meditate.</source>
        <target>אחרי שמדט בערך 10 חודשים פאלדן דורג'ה נעלם ב11 בנובמבר2006 הוא לא הבסיר את עצמו ויש כאלו שמאמינים שהוא נחטף, מאמיניו טענו שהוא העמיק אל תוך היער במטרה למצוא מקום שקט יותר למדוט.</target>
      </trans-unit>

      <trans-unit id="1">
        <source>Police abandoned a search for him after the possibility of foul play was eliminated. Suspecting money laundering, the authorities froze the bank account of the local committee managing the crowds, which had gathered more than Rs. 600,000 ($7950), but they found no evidence.</source>
        <target>, המשטרה הפסיקה את החיפושים אחריו כשהיה ברור ששופ פשע לא בוצע, ובעקבות חשד למרמות כספים הקפיאה המשטרה את חשבון הבנק שתפח מתרומות עד ל 600,000 רופיות (7950$) אך הם לא מצאו שום הוכחות.</target>
      </trans-unit>

      <trans-unit id="1">
        <source>On 19 March, a group of Palden Dorje's followers met with him about 2 miles (3 kilometers) southwest of his meditation site. They say they spoke to him for thirty minutes, during which Palden Dorje said: "There is no peace here" and that he would return in six years, which would be in 2011 or 2012. He left a message for his parents telling them not to worry.</source>
        <target>ב19 למרץ קבוצה של מאמיניו פגשה בו במרחק 3 ק"מ ממקום המדיטציה הראשון שלו הם דיברו איתו כ 30 דקות לערך והוא אמר:" אין שלוה פה ואני אחזור בעוד 6 שנים " שזה אומר ב2011 או 2012, והשאיר מסר להוריו לא לדאוג.</target>
      </trans-unit>

      <trans-unit id="1">
        <source>On 25 December 2006, villagers in Bara district spotted Palden Dorje meditating. He was carrying a sword for protection in the jungle, reminding reporters that "Even Gautama Buddha had to protect himself," and claimed to have eaten nothing but herbs in the interim.</source>
        <target>ב25 דצמבר2006 כפריים במחוז בארה  ראו את פאלדן דןרג'ה מודט, הוא נשא עימו חרב להגנה בג'ונגל והזכיר לכתבים שאפילו גאוטמה בודהא היה צריך להגן על עצמו וטען שכל מה שהוא אוכל זה צמחים שהוא מלקט ביער.</target>
      </trans-unit>

      <trans-unit id="1">
        <source>He reiterated his six year commitment, and said he would allow people to come and observe him, as long as they remained at some distance and didn't bother him. When a reporter pointed out that pilgrims to his meditation site would be making donations in his name, he asked for the donations to not be abused or used for commercial purposes. A new wave of visitors came to see him and pray at his new meditation spot. On 8 March 2007 he left Bara district to again find a quieter place to meditate.</source>
        <target>הוא המשיך את תקופת התחייבותו לתרגול בודהיסטי ואמר שהוא יאפשר לאנשים לבוא ולצפות בו כל עוד הם במרחק מה ממנו ולא יטרידו אותו, כשהכתב ציין באוזניו שהמאמינים שמגיעים נותנים תרומה על שמו הוא ביקש שלא ישתמשו בתרומות למטרות עסקים או שימוש לא טהור, גל חדש של מבקרים הגיע להתפלל במקומו החדש. ב8 למרץ 2007 הוא עזב את מחוז בארה למצוא מקום יותר שקט למדוט.</target>
      </trans-unit>

      <trans-unit id="1">
        <source>On 26 March 2007, Inspector Rameshwor Yadav of the Area Police Post Nijgadh, found Palden Dorje inside a bunker-like ditch seven feet square. A police team under Yadav's command had gone to the place after word had spread of Palden Dorje meditating underground. “His face was clean and hair was combed well,” – Yadav said.</source>
        <target>ב 26 למרץ2007 מצא המפקח רמשוואר יאדב ממשטרת ניג'גאד את פאלדן דורג'ה בתוך חפירה באדמה כמו בונקר ברוחב 3 מטרים רבועים :"פניו היו נקיים ושערו מסורק היטב " אמר.</target>
      </trans-unit>

      <trans-unit id="1">
        <source>According to him, the bunker had been cemented from all sides and fitted with a tiled roof. Indra Lama, a local deployed as Palden Dorje's caretaker since the beginning of his intensive meditation, said the bunker was prepared per Palden Dorje's request. “After granting audience a week ago, he expressed his desire to meditate inside the ground; so we built it,” – he said.</source>
        <target>המפקח הבונקר היה משוריין במלט עם גג משופע, אינדרה לאמה , המשגיח המקומי של פאלדן דורג'ה מתחילת תקופת המדיטציה האינטנסיבית אמר שהבונקר הוכן כמצוותו של פאלדן דורג'ה לפני כשבוע כי הוא הביע את רצונו למדוט בתוך האדמה.</target>
      </trans-unit>

      <trans-unit id="1">
        <source>On 2 August 2007, Palden Dorje</source>
        <target>ב 2 לאוגוסט 2007 פאלדן דורג'ה</target>
      </trans-unit>

      <trans-unit id="1">
        <source>addressed a large crowd</source>
        <target>דיבר</target>
      </trans-unit>

      <trans-unit id="1">
        <source>in Halkhoriya jungle in Bara district of southern Nepal. The Namo Buddha Tapoban Committee, which is devoted to looking after Palden Dorje, assembled the meeting.</source>
        <target>לקהל רב בג'ונגל של האלקוריה במחוז בארה בדרום נפאל, האחראים לארגון הנאום הם  מועצת הנאמו בודהא טאפובן.</target>
      </trans-unit>

      <trans-unit id="1">
        <source>A notice about the boy's first-ever preaching was broadcast by a local FM radio station, and the committee also invited people by telephone. Around three thousand people gathered to listen to Palden Dorje's address. A video was made of the event. According to Upendra Lamichhane, a blogger who wrote an article and took pictures of the meeting, Palden Dorje's message was, "The only way we can save this nation is through spirituality".</source>
        <target>הודעה על נאומו הראשון של הנער התפרסמה בתחנת רדיו מקומית והמועצה גם היזמינה אנשים בטלפון, כ 3000 אנשים התאספו להקשיב לפאלדן דורג'ה, הארוע צולם בוידאו ולפי הבלוגר אופנדרה לאמיצ'אנה שכתב מאמר על הארוע המסר שהועבר היה:" הדרך היחידה בה נוכל להציל אומה זו היא על ידי רוחנית"</target>
      </trans-unit>

      <trans-unit id="1">
        <source>This was his speech:</source>
        <target>וזה היה נאומו:</target>
      </trans-unit>

      <trans-unit id="1">
        <source>Palden Dorje is a member of the</source>
        <target>פאלדן דורג'ה הוא חלק מקהילת</target>
      </trans-unit>

      <trans-unit id="1">
        <source>Tamang</source>
        <target>"טאמאנג"</target>
      </trans-unit>

      <trans-unit id="1">
        <source>community, of which a majority practices</source>
        <target> שברובה מתרגלת</target>
      </trans-unit>

      <trans-unit id="1">
        <source>Vajrayana Buddhism</source>
        <target>ואג'ראיאנה בודהיזם.</target>
      </trans-unit>

      <trans-unit id="1">
        <source>Palden Dorje's story gained popularity because it resembled a legend from the Jataka Nidanakatha about</source>
        <target>סיפורו של פאלדן דורג'ה התפרסם כיוון שהוא מאוד דומה לסיפור הקלאסי  מה"ג'אטאקה נידנאקאטהה על</target>
      </trans-unit>

      <trans-unit id="1">
        <source>Gautama Buddha's</source>
        <target> גאוטאמה בודהא</target>
      </trans-unit>

      <trans-unit id="1">
        <source>enlightenment, so much so that some devotees claimed Palden Dorje was the reincarnation of a Buddha.</source>
        <target> שהגיע להארה, הוא כ"כ דומה עד שכמה נזירים טענו שפאלדן דורג'ה הוא התגלגלות הנשמה של בודהא.</target>
      </trans-unit>

      <trans-unit id="1">
        <source>However, on 8 November 2005 Dorje arose and said: “Tell the people not to call me a Buddha. I don't have the Buddha's energy. I am at the level of a rimpoche.” A rimpoche is a teacher, which indicates he believes he has achieved a significant amount. He said that he will need six more years of meditation before he may become a Buddha.</source>
        <target>, אך ב 8 לנובמבר 2005 קם פאלדן דורג'ה ואמר" אל תאמרו לאנשים שלא יקראו לי בודהא, אין לי את כוחו של בודהא אני ברמתו של רימפושה ,(מורה אשר נראה שיש לו כוחות מסוימים, הוא אמר שיצטרך 6 שנים נוספות לפחות עד שיהפוך ל"בודהא".</target>
      </trans-unit>

      <trans-unit id="1">
        <source>According to his followers, Palden Dorje may have reached the stage of a</source>
        <target>לפי מאמיניו של פאלדן דורג'ה הוא נמצא בשלב של</target>
      </trans-unit>

      <trans-unit id="1">
        <source>Bodhisattva </source>
        <target>בודהיסאטווה</target>
      </trans-unit>

      <trans-unit id="1">
        <source>a person on the path to attaining full enlightenment or buddhahood for the benefit of all sentient beings. According to the historical Buddha, Gautama Buddha, there were innumerable Buddhas before him and infinite Buddhas to come. Proponents also claim that Palden Dorje might also be</source>
        <target>אדם שנמצא בדרך להשגת הארה או אחוות הבודהא למען הושעת היצורים החיים, לפי הבודהא ההיסטורי, גאוטמה בודהא, היו לא מעט בודהא לפניו ויהיו אין סוף בודהא אחריו, אנשי דת גם אומרים שיתכן שפאלדן דורג'ה הוא</target>
      </trans-unit>

      <trans-unit id="1">
        <source>Maitreya</source>
        <target>"מאיטרייה בודהיסאטווה",</target>
      </trans-unit>

      <trans-unit id="1">
        <source>Bodhisattva, the predicted successor to the historical Buddha.</source>
        <target>הממשיך של בודהא הידוע.</target>
      </trans-unit>

      <trans-unit id="1">
        <source>His mother's name is Maya Devi Tamang, the same first name as Buddha's mother. It is reported that his mother fainted when she found out that her son intended to meditate for an indefinite period.</source>
        <target>שם אימו של פאלדן דורג'ה הוא מאיה דווי טאמאנג, שמה הראשון זהה לשם אימו של בודהא, לפי הדיווחים אימו איבדה את הכרתה כששמעה שבנה מתכוון למדוט לתקופה לא ידועה.</target>
      </trans-unit>

      <trans-unit id="1">
        <source>Those who have called him the "reincarnation of Buddha" have been criticised. Gautama Buddha taught that after</source>
        <target>היו ביקורות על אלו שקראו לו "התגלגלות של הבודהא", הבודהא בעצמו לימד שאחרי שהיגעת למצב</target>
      </trans-unit>

      <trans-unit id="1">
        <source>parinirvana</source>
        <target>בודהא</target>
      </trans-unit>

      <trans-unit id="1">
        <source>there is no more rebirth, therefore it is impossible to be a "reincarnation of Buddha", but it is possible to be another Buddha, another who has attained, or will attain, enlightenment.</source>
        <target>אין יותר לידה מחדש אך בהחלט יתכן שנולד בודהא חדש שהגיע או יגיע להארה.</target>
      </trans-unit>

      <trans-unit id="1">
        <source>An average human being who stops drinking will die of dehydration in three to four days. According to the Guinness Book of Records the longest time a human has survived without water is 18 days. Palden Dorje, on the other hand, does not appear to break his meditation to eat or drink.</source>
        <target>אדם ממוצע שהפסיק לשתות ימות מהתיבשות תוך 3-4 ימים לפי ספר גינס והשיא שנרשם הוא על אדם ששרד 18 יום בלי לשתות, פאלדן דורג'ה כפי הנראה אינו מפסיק למדוט כדי לשתות או לאכול.</target>
      </trans-unit>

      <trans-unit id="1">
        <source>Palden Dorje was observed not to leave the tree at least during the daytime, but nobody was allowed to approach him too closely. Between 5:00 p.m. and 5:00 a.m. nobody was allowed to see him, and a screen was erected for that purpose. Many people speculated that he ate and drank water during that time.</source>
        <target>, הוא לא נראה עוזב את העץ, לפחות לא במשך היום אך אף אחד לא הורשה להתקרב אליו בין 5 איה"צ ל 5 בבוקר אף אחד לא הורשה לראותו ומסך הותקן שם לצורך זה,הרבה אנשים שיערו שהוא אוכל ושותה בזמן הזה.</target>
      </trans-unit>

      <trans-unit id="1">
        <source>Some supporters believe that discussions of</source>
        <target>לתומכים זה ברור שאין מה לדבר על</target>
      </trans-unit>

      <trans-unit id="1">
        <source>http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Inedia</source>
        <target></target>
      </trans-unit>

      <trans-unit id="1">
        <source>inedia</source>
        <target>אינדיה,</target>
      </trans-unit>

      <trans-unit id="1">
        <source>are irrelevant, and that the ability to sit nearly motionless in the same position day after day, with no regard for extremes of weather including a cold winter and a monsoon season, is notable. For example, American writer George Saunders visited Palden Dorje and observed him through a single night, and was impressed by Palden Dorje's perfectly still stature, even during an evening climate that seemed unbearably cold to the much better clothed journalist.</source>
        <target>ושהיכולת לשבת ללא תנועה באותה התנוחה יום אחרי יום ללא התיחסות למזג האויר הקר בחורף והגשום בעונת המונסונים היא בהחלט ניתנת להבנה.
לדוגמא הכתב האמריקאי ג'ורג' סאונדרס ביקר את פאלדן דורג'ה ובחן אותו במשך לילה אחד והתרשם מישיבתו היציבה ללא תזוזה אפילו בקור הלילי שהיה קשה לג'ורג' הלבוש בבגדים חמים.
</target>
      </trans-unit>

      <trans-unit id="1">
        <source>In December 2005, a nine-member government committee led by Gunjaman Lama watched Palden Dorje carefully for 48 hours and observed him not to take any food or water during that time. A video recording was also made of this test. However, they were unable to approach closer than 3 meters or take readings of his vital signs. The Nepalese government planned a more careful scientific study, but the plan was never carried out.</source>
        <target>בדצמבר 2005 מועצה ממשלתית בת 9 חברים בראשות גונג'אמאן לאמה בחנה את פאלדן דורג'ה במשך 48 שעות וראו שהוא לא שתה ולא אכל במשך כל הזמן הזה, הקלטת וידאו גם נעשתה באותו האופן,אך הם לא יכלו להתקרב יותר מ3 מטרים ממנו ולראות את הפרטים מקרוב, ממשלת נפאל תיכננה לבצע מעקב יותר מקיף אך תןכניתם לא יצאה לפועל.</target>
      </trans-unit>

      <trans-unit id="1">
        <source>In 2007, the Discovery Channel produced a documentary titled</source>
        <target>ב 2007 ערוץ דיסקברי יצא עם סרטון דוקומנטרי בשם</target>
      </trans-unit>

      <trans-unit id="1">
        <source>The Boy With Divine Powers</source>
        <target>"הנער עם הכוחות האלוהיים"</target>
      </trans-unit>

      <trans-unit id="1">
        <source>On their first, four-day attempt, the film crew was required to stay outside a guarded barbed-wire fence, and their camera's infrared capabilities did not pick up evidence of a body at the base of the tree where Palden Dorje sat during their non-stop recording. On a second attempt a few weeks later, however, the film crew was able to film Palden Dorje continuously for 96 hours, day and night, during which time he did not drink any fluids or eat any food. According to scientists on the documentary, an average person would be expected to die from kidney failure after four days without drinking any fluids. The boy showed no signs of classical physical deterioration caused by dehydration. A close inspection by the film crew of the area around the tree where Palden Dorje was sitting revealed no hidden food supply or water pipes.</source>
        <target> במשך 4 הימים הראשונים הצוות נאלץ להישאר מחוץ לתחום הגדר וציוד הצילום שלהם שכלל מצלמוצ עם עדשת איפרא אדום לא קלטו את דמותו של הנער בתחתית העץ, בניסיון השני מספר שבועות לאחר מכן הם הצליחו לצלם את פאלדן דורג'ה במשך 96 שעות יו ולילה שבמהלכם הוא לא שתה נוזלים ולא אכל אוכל, הנער לא הראה סימני מצוקה של התייבשות.</target>
      </trans-unit>

      <trans-unit id="1">
        <source>On 10 November 2008, Palden Dorje</source>
        <target></target>
      </trans-unit>

      <trans-unit id="1">
        <source>reappeared and spoke</source>
        <target></target>
      </trans-unit>

      <trans-unit id="1">
        <source>to a group of devotees in the remote jungle of Ratanpur, 150 km (95 miles) southeast of Kathmandu, near Nijgadh. His hair was shoulder-length and his body was wrapped in a white cloth.</source>
        <target>ב10 לנובמבר 2008 פאלדן דורג'ה הופיע מחדש ודיבר לקבוצת מאמינים ביער של ראטנאפור 150 ק"מ דרום מזרחית מקטמנדו ליד ניג'גאד, שערו היה בגובה הכתפיים והוא היה עטוף בבד לבן.</target>
      </trans-unit>

      <trans-unit id="1">
        <source>His devotees believe he attained enlightenment at Bodh Gaya in Bihar, which borders Nepal – the place where Siddartha Gautama attained enlightenment.</source>
        <target>מאמיניו חשבו שהוא הגיע להארה בבודגאיה במדינת ביהאר, הודו, על גבול נפאל,המקום בו סידהארטה גאוטמה הגיע להארה,</target>
      </trans-unit>

      <trans-unit id="1">
        <source>biography_translated_by</source>
        <target></target>
      </trans-unit>

<!-- утф -->
    </body>
  </file>
</xliff>